<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Home</title>
  </properties>
    
  <body>
    <section name="Cyklotron">
      <subsection name="Introduction">
        <p>Cyklotron is a content management system - an application for easy development and 
        management of websites. </p>
        <p> Cyklotron project is sponsored by major player in the Non Governmental Organizations 
        domain, and thus it's primary focus is serving the needs of NGOs, but the developed software 
        will be also useful and available for commercial entities.</p>
        <p>Cyklotron is based on earlier CykloKlon project. You can see Cyklotron in 
        action on these major NGO websites in Poland: 
        <a href="http://www.ngo.pl">http://www.ngo.pl</a> and 
        <a href="http://www.niepelnosprawni.info">http://www.niepelnosprawni.info</a>.</p> 
        <p>It is developed as an Open Source project, and is based on a large number of open source 
        libraries and tools. The software developed in the course of the project will be available 
        for any non-commercial or commercial use on the terms of liberal BSD license.</p>
        <p>The 2.0 release of Cyklotron software is a major milestone in it's development. Cyklotron
        has been recently ported to <a href="http://objectledge.org">ObjectLedge</a> and 
        <a href="http://coral.objectledge.org">Coral</a> libraries, signigifactly enhancing it's performance.</p>
        <p>Cyklotron CMS is capable of running very large sites. The ngo.pl installation features
        50+ virtual sites with 60000+ documents, and another 1000 is added each month. It also delivers
        impressive performance on a relatively modest hardware. Ngo.pl serves 2.5 million dynamically
        rendered pages a month, while running on $1500 dual Athlon machine, and the bottleneck for
        most of the time is the capacity of 2Mbit internet link.</p>
        <p>Cyklotron is a mature product. It is in the making since September 2001, and ngo.pl site is
        running Cyklotron since March 2003. Tens of programmer-months were spent on weeding out the
        bugs and improving performance.</p>
      </subsection>
      <!--
      <subsection name="Project scope">
        <p>
          Here's a project categorization entry along the lines of SourceForge's Trove. It provides
          give some basic informations about the project in condensed form.
          <ul>
            <li>Development Status: <b>Alpha</b></li>
            <li>Environment: <b>Web Environment</b></li>
            <li>Intended Audience: <b>Developers, Information Technology</b></li>
            <li>License: <b>OSI Approved BSD</b></li>
            <li>Natural Language: <b>English</b></li>
            <li>Operating System: <b>OS Independent</b></li>
            <li>Programming Language: <b>Java</b></li>
            <li>Topic: <b>Internet&gt;HTTP/WWW&gt;Site management</b></li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Why the name?">
      </subsection>
      -->
      
      <subsection name="License">
       <p>
        <a href="http://opensource.org/docs/certification_mark.php">
          <img alt="Open Source Certified!" style="border:none; float:left; margin-right:10px;" src="http://opensource.org/graphics/osi-certified-120x100.png"/>
        </a>
        <b>This software is OSI Certified Open Source Software.<br/>
        OSI Certified is a certification mark of the Open Source Initiative.</b><br/>
        <br/>
        Cyklotron is made available on the terms of BSD <a href="license.html">license</a>,
        which has been certified by the <a href="http://opensource.org">Open Source Initiative</a>
        organization.<br/>
        <br/>
        In short, you are granted the right to use Cyklotron in any endevaour commercial,
        or not, and create derived works, as long as you give apropriate credit to the authors.
       </p>
      </subsection>
      
    </section>
    
  </body>
</document>
  
